<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Applications on Government Services Documentation</title><link>/categories/applications/</link><description>Recent content in Applications on Government Services Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/applications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apply for First Class Graduate Certificate</title><link>/certificates/41_apply_for_first_class_graduate_certificate/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/certificates/41_apply_for_first_class_graduate_certificate/</guid><description>Apply for First Class Graduate Certificate From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
The first graduate students of the family of Tamil Nadu can avail this benefit. This will exempt them from tuition fees. The first graduate students who want to avail this benefit can use government and government assistance through various colleges.
Eligibility The first graduate in the family A person who is studying in a family when the course is completed This concession is for a person in the family How to Apply for First Class Graduate Certificate in Tamil Nadu Let&amp;rsquo;s see how to apply.</description></item><item><title>Apply for Marriage Certificate Online in Tamil Nadu</title><link>/certificates/34_apply_for_marriage_certificate_online/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/certificates/34_apply_for_marriage_certificate_online/</guid><description>Apply for Marriage Certificate Online in Tamil Nadu From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
A full-fledged comment on how to make marriage certificates has been released in Tamil Nadu.
Background Earlier in Tamil Nadu, people had to wait for caste and community certificates from the government. People had to wait for a long time to get these certificates. Now, these certificates are available in the country where the government has become a digital commentary and can be used to ease the process.</description></item><item><title>Apply for Pension Online</title><link>/welfare-schemes/35_apply_for_pension_online/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/welfare-schemes/35_apply_for_pension_online/</guid><description>Apply for Pension Online From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
Required Documents Aadhar card Family card Birth certificate Death certificate (if applicable) Bank passbook How to Apply First Program: Access the Portal First, go to https://tnega.tn.gov.in/ and click on Citizen login. Enter your User Name and Password and click on Captcha Code. People who do not have an account should click on New User and sign up.</description></item><item><title>How to Apply for a New Ration Card Online</title><link>/ration-card-services/06_apply_for_new_ration_card_online_en/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ration-card-services/06_apply_for_new_ration_card_online_en/</guid><description>How to Apply for a New Ration Card Online From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
Ration card is a very important document for all people in Tamil Nadu. In the past, people used to spend many hours going to the Taluk office for tasks like applying for a new card, correcting errors in ration cards, adding new members, or removing members. Now, as everything in the country is being digitized, there is a way to apply for a new ration card online.</description></item><item><title>How to Apply for a Passport</title><link>/passport-services/62_apply_for_a_passport/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/passport-services/62_apply_for_a_passport/</guid><description>How to Apply for a Passport From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
Through the newly established &amp;ldquo;Passport Seva Kendras&amp;rdquo; (PSK), it is now easy to apply for a passport online.
Online Application Registration Previously, to obtain a passport, one had to go to the passport office and submit documents in paper format, which caused delays. To rectify this situation, the new &amp;ldquo;Passport Seva Kendras&amp;rdquo; (PSK) initiative has been introduced.</description></item><item><title>How to Apply for OBC Certificate Online</title><link>/certificates/03_apply_for_obc_certificate_online_en/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/certificates/03_apply_for_obc_certificate_online_en/</guid><description>How to Apply for OBC Certificate Online From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
Those belonging to Backward Classes and Most Backward Classes will require an OBC (Other Backward Class) certificate to avail employment and educational opportunities from the Central Government.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see how to apply for and obtain them.
Who Can Apply for OBC Certificate? Those who wish to obtain OBC certificate should not belong to categories like SC / ST.</description></item><item><title>How to Download Ration Card Application</title><link>/ration-card-services/60_download_ration_card_application/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ration-card-services/60_download_ration_card_application/</guid><description>How to Download Ration Card Application From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
Step-by-Step Process Step 1: Access the Portal To download a ration card application online, those belonging to Tamil Nadu should go to the website https://www.tnpds.gov.in/. Step 2: Login On the left side of the website, click on the &amp;lsquo;Beneficiary Login&amp;rsquo; option. Step 3: Check Service Status On the right side, click on the option to know the service status related to the card.</description></item></channel></rss>