<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welfare Schemes on Government Services Documentation</title><link>/categories/welfare-schemes/</link><description>Recent content in Welfare Schemes on Government Services Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/welfare-schemes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apply for Pension Online</title><link>/welfare-schemes/35_apply_for_pension_online/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/welfare-schemes/35_apply_for_pension_online/</guid><description>Apply for Pension Online From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
Required Documents Aadhar card Family card Birth certificate Death certificate (if applicable) Bank passbook How to Apply First Program: Access the Portal First, go to https://tnega.tn.gov.in/ and click on Citizen login. Enter your User Name and Password and click on Captcha Code. People who do not have an account should click on New User and sign up.</description></item><item><title>How to Apply for a New Ration Card Online</title><link>/ration-card-services/06_apply_for_new_ration_card_online_en/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ration-card-services/06_apply_for_new_ration_card_online_en/</guid><description>How to Apply for a New Ration Card Online From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
Ration card is a very important document for all people in Tamil Nadu. In the past, people used to spend many hours going to the Taluk office for tasks like applying for a new card, correcting errors in ration cards, adding new members, or removing members. Now, as everything in the country is being digitized, there is a way to apply for a new ration card online.</description></item><item><title>How to Download Ration Card Application</title><link>/ration-card-services/60_download_ration_card_application/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ration-card-services/60_download_ration_card_application/</guid><description>How to Download Ration Card Application From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
Step-by-Step Process Step 1: Access the Portal To download a ration card application online, those belonging to Tamil Nadu should go to the website https://www.tnpds.gov.in/. Step 2: Login On the left side of the website, click on the &amp;lsquo;Beneficiary Login&amp;rsquo; option. Step 3: Check Service Status On the right side, click on the option to know the service status related to the card.</description></item><item><title>How to Download Ration Card Online</title><link>/ration-card-services/61_download_ration_card_online/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ration-card-services/61_download_ration_card_online/</guid><description>How to Download Ration Card Online From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
Step-by-Step Process Step 1: Access the Portal To download a ration card online, those belonging to Tamil Nadu should go to the website https://www.tnpds.gov.in/. Step 2: Login On the left side of the website, click on the &amp;lsquo;Beneficiary Login&amp;rsquo; option. Step 3: Enter Details Then, enter the mobile number linked to the ration card in the field.</description></item><item><title>How to Link Mobile Number with Ration Card</title><link>/ration-card-services/07_verify_mobile_number_on_ration_card_en/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ration-card-services/07_verify_mobile_number_on_ration_card_en/</guid><description>How to Link Mobile Number with Ration Card From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
Ration card is a mandatory document for every Indian citizen. Starting from mobile number, Aadhar number, adding new members, removing names, removing names of deceased persons, all recent details and changes must be updated.
More importantly, if you have bought a new mobile number or if your mobile number is wrong, you must update it in the ration card.</description></item><item><title>How to Remove a Family Member's Name from the Ration Card</title><link>/ration-card-services/08_remove_family_member_from_ration_card_en/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ration-card-services/08_remove_family_member_from_ration_card_en/</guid><description>How to Remove a Family Member&amp;rsquo;s Name from the Ration Card From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
Step-by-Step Process Step 1: Access the Portal To remove a name from the ration card online, those belonging to Tamil Nadu should go to the website https://www.tnpds.gov.in/ (the website address varies from state to state). On the website, click on &amp;lsquo;Beneficiary Login&amp;rsquo;. Step 2: Login Process Then, enter the mobile number that you have linked with the ration card in the given field.</description></item><item><title>If the Ration Card is Deactivated, How to Activate It?</title><link>/ration-card-services/09_reactivate_deleted_ration_card_en/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ration-card-services/09_reactivate_deleted_ration_card_en/</guid><description>If the Ration Card is Deactivated, How to Activate It? From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
All ration card holders must compulsorily buy ration items every month. If they do not buy them regularly, the ration card will be cancelled. Based on the number of family members and economic status, ration items like sugar and rice are provided under the Public Distribution System according to the card.</description></item></channel></rss>