<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Identity Documents on Government Services Documentation</title><link>/categories/identity-documents/</link><description>Recent content in Identity Documents on Government Services Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/identity-documents/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Apply for a Passport</title><link>/passport-services/62_apply_for_a_passport/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/passport-services/62_apply_for_a_passport/</guid><description>How to Apply for a Passport From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
Through the newly established &amp;ldquo;Passport Seva Kendras&amp;rdquo; (PSK), it is now easy to apply for a passport online.
Online Application Registration Previously, to obtain a passport, one had to go to the passport office and submit documents in paper format, which caused delays. To rectify this situation, the new &amp;ldquo;Passport Seva Kendras&amp;rdquo; (PSK) initiative has been introduced.</description></item><item><title>How to Get e-PAN</title><link>/pan-card-services/14_get_e_pan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pan-card-services/14_get_e_pan/</guid><description>How to Get e-PAN From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
Steps to Get e-PAN Step 1: Access the Portal Log in to the website https://www.incometax.gov.in/iec/foportal Click on the &amp;lsquo;Instant e-PAN&amp;rsquo; option. Step 2: Select New e-PAN Next, click on &amp;lsquo;New e-PAN&amp;rsquo;. Step 3: Enter Details Enter your existing PAN number If you have forgotten your PAN number, enter your Aadhaar number. Step 4: Accept Terms and Conditions Read the terms and conditions and click &amp;lsquo;Accept&amp;rsquo; Step 5: OTP Verification Then enter the OTP sent to your registered mobile number.</description></item><item><title>If You Lose Your PAN Card or Forget Your PAN Number</title><link>/pan-card-services/13_retrieve_lost_or_forgotten_pan_number/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pan-card-services/13_retrieve_lost_or_forgotten_pan_number/</guid><description>If You Lose Your PAN Card or Forget Your PAN Number From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
If you have applied for PAN Card Apply, you will have to use that PAN number for the entire day. It is an offence under the Act to use multiple PAN cards. A fine will be imposed.
In some cases, you may lose your PAN card. You may also have forgotten the PAN number of that PAN card.</description></item><item><title>Reprint or Update PAN Card</title><link>/pan-card-services/40_reprint_or_update_pan_card/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pan-card-services/40_reprint_or_update_pan_card/</guid><description>Reprint or Update PAN Card From Birth to Death!
Government Documents / Services - Guidebook
It is very easy to make a new PAN card in the country. You do not need to submit any documents by post. PAN card changes, address or other details can be easily updated online. By this PAN card, if you are born, you can make changes.
Personal details corrected in PAN card or address can be updated.</description></item></channel></rss>